Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Birmingham, Mich.) records, 1834-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Birmingham, Mich.) records 1834-1985
First Presbyterian Church (Birmingham, Mich.).
6 microfilm reels
86826 Ba Microcopy
Registers of membership, baptisms, marriages and deaths, session minutes, trustee minutes, treasurer's records, and records of the women's foreign missionary society, ladies church society, and Presbyterian women's union.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The microfilmed records were donated by the church (donor no. 7228 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church of Birmingham, Michigan was established in 1834.
The First Presbyterian Church of Birmingham record group includes session minutes; trustee minutes; registers of membership, births, marriages, and deaths; deacons' minutes; treasurer's records; minutes and ledgers from church women's organization; and miscellaneous other materials.
Subjects:
Birmingham (Mich.)--Church history.; Missionaries.; Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)--Missions--Societies, etc.; Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)--Michigan--Birmingham.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Birmingham.; Women--Michigan--Birmingham--Societies and clubs; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Birmingham.
- Session Minutes
  - July 2, 1834-April 5, 1859 (Reel 2)
    (Vol. 1)
  - April 13, 1859-December 21, 1884 (Reel 2)
    (Vol. 2)
  - August 27, 1884-March 30, 1913 (Reel 2)
    (Vol. 3)
  - June 29, 1913-April 6, 1927 (Reel 2)
    (Vol. 4)
  - May 1951-December 1965 (Reel 5)
  - January 1966-December 1977 (Reel 6)
- Trustee Minutes
  - December 17, 1835-January 30, 1877 (Reel 2)
  - 1878-1903 (Reel 4)
  - January 14, 1915-May 7, 1937 (includes Charter of 1907 (Reel 1)
  - 1963-1975 (Reel 4)
- Treasurer's Records
  - March 31, 1930-April 9, 1940 (Reel 1)
- Deacon's Minutes
  - 1971-1980 (Reel 4)
- Registers
  - Membership
    - 1865-1899 (Reel 3)
    - 1905-1976 (Reel 3)
  - Baptisms
    - 1912-1924 (Reel 3)
    - 1931-1976 (Reel 3)
  - Marriages
    - 1905-1919 (Reel 3)
    - 1931-1976 (Reel 3)
  - Deaths
    - 1938-1976 (Reel 3)
  - Membership
    - 1977-1985 (Reel 4)
  - Baptisms
    - 1977-1985 (Reel 4)
  - Marriages
    - 1977-1985 (Reel 4)
  - Deaths
    - 1977-1980 (Reel 4)
- Women's Organizations
  - Ledgers
    - Ladies Church Society
      - 1881-1913 (Reel 2)
      - 1914-1932 (Reel 2)
  - Minutes
    - Women's Foreign Missionary Society, March 7, 1888-August 7, 1912 (Reel 2)
    - Ladies Church Society, April 1924-March 1932 (Reel 2)
      (Vol. 5)
    - Women's Union, March 1932-March 1933 (Reel 2)
      (Vol. 6)
- Miscellaneous Church Records 1834-1930s
  - Articles of Association, April 17, 1907 (Reel 2)
  - Miscellaneous Membership Lists, late 1800s (Reel 2)
  - 100th Anniversary Celebration, 1934 (Reel 2)